The Purge: Anarchy is a horror, thriller film directed by James DeMonaco.
One night per year, the government sanctions a 12-hour period in which citizens can commit any
crime they wish -- including murder -- without fear of punishment or imprisonment.
Leo, a sergeant who lost his son, plans a vigilante
mission of revenge during the mayhem.
However, instead of a death-dealing avenger, he becomes the unexpected protector of four
innocent strangers who desperately need his help if they are to survive the night.
Sergeant, played by Frank Grillo.
Eva Sanchez, played by Carmen Ejogo.
Shane, played by Zach Gilford.
Carmelo, played by Michael Kenneth Williams.
Liz, played by Kiele Sanchez.
Cali, played by Zoë Soul.
The Purge: Anarchy is a 2014 American action horror film
written and directed by James DeMonaco.
A sequel to  The Purge and the second installment in the Purge franchise, the film stars
Frank Grillo, Carmen Ejogo, Zach Gilford, Kiele Sanchez, and Michael K.
Edwin Hodge reprised his role from the first film.
It was released worldwide on July 18, 2014.
The film is set in a near-future dystopian United States, ruled by a totalitarian government known as the New Founding Fathers of
America (NFFA), that is preparing for the annual Purge, a 12-hour event that legalizes all crimes without authorities.
However, an anti-Purge resistance group opposes the NFFA and the Purge.
The film grossed over $111 million and received mixed reviews from critics, who praised it as an
improvement over its predecessor, but criticized its clichéd formula and screenplay.
While the first film was set largely in one house, Anarchy takes place around the Greater Los
Angeles area and shows more of what happens to the surroundings during the event.
A third film in the series, The Purge: Election
Year, was released on July 1, 2016.
The film explores themes of sniper, psychopath, bus, assault rifle, dystopia.
The tone is dark and intense.